<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Home</title>
    <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Car Price Prediction</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/car_price_prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/car_price_prediction/</guid>
      <description>Using the car prices dataset that can be found here containing 26 features such as car name, number of doors, and engine size, and 204 instances of those features, I predict the car price.
The first few feature distributions looks like this;
  The distribution of the car prices looks like a log-normal distribution, as can be see below;
  I perfomed some exploratory data anylsis to get a feel of the data and its features, for example a good feature to predict price is engine size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zambia&#39;s Best President</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/blog/who_was_zambia_s_best_pres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/blog/who_was_zambia_s_best_pres/</guid>
      <description>Background The Republic of Zambia is a landlocked country at the crossroads of Central, Southern and East Africa. Zambia was previously known as Northern Rhodesia(1911 - 1964), before she gained independence from british rule in 1964. Dr. Kenneth Kaunda became the first president of the Republic of Zambia.
Zambia has seen a total of six presidents since independence; she turns 57 years old this year. This article attempts to name the best Zambian president in managing the economy by analysing the WDI_Data (World Development Indicators) dataset from The Word Bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Books</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/blog/books_for_datascience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/blog/books_for_datascience/</guid>
      <description>This post points to some resources to learn data science, it highly emphasises machine learning applications, and statistics &amp;amp; probability.
Here are some free and/or paid resources to learn data science.
Mathematics for Data Science
   Field Book     Statistics: An Introduction to Statistical Learning   Statistics(Advanced): Elements of Statistical Learning   Statistics and Probability: Python for Probability, Statistics, and Machine Learning   Linear Algebra, Calculus, and Mathematics: Foundations of Mathematics for Computer Science: A Visual Approach    Statistical Machine Learning/Deep Learning</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language Translation</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/translation/</guid>
      <description>The objective of this challenge is to create a machine translation system capable of converting text from French into Fongbe or Ewe. Fongbe is the major Gbe language of Benin (with approximately 4.1 million speakers), while Ewe is spoken in Togo and southeastern Ghana by approximately 4.5 million people as a first language and by a million others as a second language.
This challenge is part of an initiative that wishes to bring down the barriers between African local language speakers and modern society; non-French/English speakers are often unable to access critical facilities like education, banking, and healthcare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market and Enrolment Analysis of Equity Students in Victoria</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/capstone_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/capstone_2020/</guid>
      <description>As an intern at the University of Melbourne, I used my data science skills to help realize the university&amp;rsquo;s objectives in student access and equity, and improved diversity in the student cohort. They wished to engage and win students of various backgrounds, including, but not limited to, Low Social-Economic student, First Nation students, and Disavantaged Background students.
I was part of a 3-person diverse team, and we examined the VTAC Masterfile dataset that comprised of more than 360 attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-armed Bandits</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/muti-armed_bandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/muti-armed_bandits/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I implemented several MAB learners. These leaners include epsilon-Greedy, UCB, and LinUCB (which is adopted from Section 3.1 of the WWW’2010 paper)
The Dataset used is a 2MB .txt file with 1000 lines corresponding to distinct site visits by users.
link to code
Multi-armed bandits (MABs) are a powerful tool in statistical machine learning: they bridge decision making, control, optimisation and learning; they address practical problems of sequential decision making while backed by elegant theoretical guarantees; and more subtly they are neither fully supervised nor unsupervised, being partial labelled by indirect rewards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Fact verification</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/automatic_fact_verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/automatic_fact_verification/</guid>
      <description>The objective of the project was to create a model capable of verifying whether a claim is true, false, or unknown; where unknown means that the model could not verify the claim given the evidence.
Evidence of claims was provided in a large 3GB wikipedia corpus containing a wiki pages.
The project is comprised to two parts.
 Information retrieval  Created a pagerank model where given a claim, it returns the top n pages related to the query/claim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment in Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/sentiment_nectar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/sentiment_nectar/</guid>
      <description>The objective of the project was to perform a city wide sentiment analysis and understand the shifts caused by weather, sporting events, and even the police among other phenomena within the city.
This project was a 5-person project. It was completed on australian cloud platform NeCTAR.
Different aspects of the project included;
 web scrapping (tweet harvesting) tweet sentiment tag automation couchbase and hadoop UI development  My resposibilities were to streamline the automotion process using Boto, and ansible, in order to create and deploy cloud instances on demand, and install all necessary software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eco Spatial Solutions</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/fastest_route/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/fastest_route/</guid>
      <description>Eco Spatial Solutions is a project to meet the objectives of the Plan Melbourne 2017-2050 project, which is a long-term plan devised to facilitate sustainable development in Melbourne’s growing future.
This project provides a solution to the Direction 6.7 of the Plan, i.e. to;
 Improve the economic recovery of waste and reduce reliance on landfill Improve waste and resource recovery systems to meet the logistical challenges of medium and higher density developments Protect waste management and resource recovery facilities from urban encroachment and assess opportunities for new waste facilities  motivation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Linear Regression Models</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/linear_regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/post/linear_regression/</guid>
      <description>I built multiple linear regression models. Collected two datasets from from here and here respectively. First task: predict salary from number of years of experience. Second task: predict miles per gallon in the Auto MPG dataset using tensorflow.    Tools used
 Python sklearn tensorflow keras  link to code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can find me on these platforms;
   Platform URL     LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremiah-munakabayo/   Github: https://github.com/jeremih4   Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/jeremih_law/   Medium: https://medium.com/@JeremiahLawrence    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
