<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Home</title>
    <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zambia&#39;s Best President</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/blog/who_was_zambia_s_best_pres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/blog/who_was_zambia_s_best_pres/</guid>
      <description>Background The Republic of Zambia is a landlocked country at the crossroads of Central, Southern, and East Africa. Zambia was previously known as Northern Rhodesia (1911 - 1964), before she gained independence from british rule in 1964. Dr Kenneth Kaunda became the first president of the Republic of Zambia.
Zambia has seen a total of six presidents since independence; she turns 57 years old this year. This article attempts to name the best Zambian president in managing the economy by analysing the WDI_Data (World Development Indicators) dataset from The Word Bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Books</title>
      <link>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/blog/books_for_datascience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Jeremih4.github.io/Jeremiah_Munakabayo_Portfolio/blog/books_for_datascience/</guid>
      <description>This post points to some resources to learn data science, it highly emphasises machine learning applications, and statistics &amp;amp; probability.
Here are some free and/or paid resources to learn data science.
Mathematics for Data Science
   Field Book     Statistics: An Introduction to Statistical Learning   Statistics(Advanced): Elements of Statistical Learning   Statistics and Probability: Python for Probability, Statistics, and Machine Learning   Linear Algebra, Calculus, and Mathematics: Foundations of Mathematics for Computer Science: A Visual Approach    Statistical Machine Learning/Deep Learning</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
